CAUTION
(注意)
(Metallic Rouge)
《金属口红》
It seems somehow
看来不知道为什么
the police got wind of Yubal's murder.
警方已经收到犹巴遇害的风声了
The security force will go to you.
维安部队会往你那里进行攻坚
If you get involved, it will be complicated. You better leave now.
要是被卷进去会很麻烦 快点离开…
I don't want to run away.
我不要逃走
What?
什么
I didn't kill him.
不是我杀的
It doesn't matter who the killer is.
真凶是谁都无所谓
The police here just want an excuse to take down CFN.
这里的警察要的只是一个 击溃CFN的借口罢了
There is an agent here.
有内应…
So the one is Phantom Verde?
难道说那个内应就是幻影的维杜吗
It is indeed possible.
这个可能性并也不是零…
So I won't run away.
所以我不要逃走
As long as I stay here, he will come to me.
只要待在这里 他就会主动来接近我
Then I'll get rid of him according to the order
然后依照指示 解决掉幻影的维杜
and get his Id.
回收他的伊德
Excuse me, are you really Miss Rouge?
不好意思 您真的是露琼小姐吗
I am Miss Rouge.
我是露琼小姐
Well,
没有啦
you really have grown up.
你这次真的长大了呢
It's none of your business.
要你管
Alright, then I'll also support…
没办法 那我也来支援…
No need.
你不用来啦
I want to go.
我想要去
I want to be there to support you.
去你那边支援你
Please let me support you.
让我来帮忙
What?
咦…
This is my free will.
这是我的自由意志
Because we are
因为我和你
neither tools nor spare parts for the Aletheia.
都不是真理部的物品和备品
Up to you.
真拿你没办法
Then I'll wait for you.
那我就等你来
Without a leader, we're in a mess.
失去了指导者 我们陷入一片混乱
I understand.
我能理解
I'd like to ask you to explain the situation again.
我想请你再详细说明一次当时状况
I have a question for you too.
我也有问题想要问你们
We don't have to listen to her.
果然没有必要听她狡辩
I think she should be executed immediately.
我认为应该马上处决掉她
I've said it many times
我说过很多次了
she might not be the real killer.
真凶不一定是她
And…
而且…
A Nean can't kill another Nean.
涅安无法杀死涅安
Do you want to trust this Nean of unknown origins?
你要相信这个来历不明的涅安吗
Eliminating all those of unknown origins
除掉所有来历不明之人
would make us no different from humans.
这样我们跟人类有何不同
But she could be from Alter.
但她也有可能是奥塔的人
That's why we need to confirm this.
所以才要来确认这一点
Calm down.
你们冷静点
Sorry.
抱歉
May I start questioning you now?
可以开始审问你了吗
You'd do so even if I say no.
就算我说不要你也会问吧
Why were you there?
你为何会出现在那里
Someone asked me to come.
因为有人叫我来
Did Yubal call you in person?
是犹巴直接叫你来的吗
He sent someone to ask me to come.
他派人传话给我
Who?
他派谁传话给你
First squad, suppress Location A.
第一小队镇压A地点
Second squad, suppress Location B.
第二小队镇压B地点
Arrest all CFN members.
将所有CFN成员逮捕
Destroy them if it's necessary.
如有必要 破坏掉也无所谓
Commence.
开始行动
What's wrong with you?
怎么了
Why don't you answer?
为何不回答
Speak up if you've been wronged.
如果你是被冤枉的话 不是更应该要说清楚吗
Are you protecting someone?
你是在保护某个人吗
But keeping silent won't help you.
但是保持沉默帮不了你
Fine.
好吧
Let's go back to the first question.
我们重新回到第一个问题
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Your name?
你的名字
Rouge Redstar.
露琼・雷德斯塔
Your date of manufacture?
你的制造日期
I don't know.
不知道
Are you from Earth?
你是从地球来的吗
You're an agent of the Aletheia, right?
你是真理部的特务吧
This is your first time on the settlement, right?
你是第一次来到居留地吧
What did you see?
你看到些什么
What do you think?
有什么感想
Those Neans who are locked up here and deprived of the freedom to die.
那些被关在这里 连求死的自由都被剥夺的涅安们
Yubal asked you to be the hope of these Neans, right?
犹巴应该有请你 成为这些涅安们的希望吧
Don't you want to save them?
你不会想要拯救他们吗
That…
那…
That's not your mission.
那并不是你的任务…
Right?
是吗
It seems Yubal has misjudged.
看来是犹巴看走眼了
You can't save the Neans.
你拯救不了涅安
Because you're confined too.
因为你也被束缚住了
You can live more freely and faithfully to your desires.
你可以更加自由 更加忠实于自己的欲望而活
Just kill those you want to kill
去杀想杀的人
and save those you want to save.
去救想救的人就好
In this way,
如此一来
you could save Sarah Fitzgerald.
你也能拯救莎拉・费兹杰罗吧
Don't you love her singing?
你不是很喜欢她的歌声吗
You are…
你是…
Kill her.
快点杀了她
Oh no.
糟糕
-Kill her. -Hurry up and open it.
-杀了她 -快点打开
She might not be the killer.
她还不一定是凶手吧
Look, she's breaking free.
你们看 她挣脱了
She wants to kill us.
她想要杀死我们啊
Right.
没…没错
She just tried to attack me.
她刚刚就是想要攻击我
Kill her.
杀了她…
Don't do this.
别这样
-Stop. -Kill her.
-快住手 -杀了她…
I don't want to hurt you guys.
我不想伤害你们
Kill her.
杀了她…
Get out of my way.
让开
It's the security force.
是维安部队
Oh no, run!
不妙 快逃啊
Stop right there!
给我站住
Get down!
跪下
Suppression on 3rd floor is completed.
第三层镇压完毕
The body of Yubal 087 was found.
发现犹巴087的遗体
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑
Are you going to abandon Yubal and run?
你要丢下犹巴逃跑吗
We have no choice now.
现在只能这么做了吧
What are you doing? Leave now!
你们在做什么 还不快走…
Don't move.
不要动
You guys better run.
你们也快点逃
Let's go, everyone!
快走吧 各位
Stand there.
站住
Miss Rouge.
露琼小姐
Leon.
里昂
The building has been surrounded on all sides.
建筑物的四周都被包围了
Follow me now.
跟我来 快点
Hurry up.
快点啊
Damn.
可恶
I lost Duma.
跟丢仲马了
Are you serious, Detective Ash?
你是认真的吗 亚许探员
This is a security operation within the settlement.
这可是在居留地内进行的维安行动
This is no small deal.
事情非同小可
Do you think this has something to do with the red suspect?
你认为这跟红色嫌犯有关吗
Your intuition again?
又是那个直觉吗
But how do you get in there?
但是你要怎么进去里面
Who do you think we are?
你以为我们是什么人
We're from the Ochrona.
我们可是守謢局耶
Wonderful. You have that kind of authority.
好好哦 这种权力
Please count me in.
也让我来参一脚吧
(Episode 4: Freedom and Phantoms)
(4 自由与幻影)
This way.
往这里
The red suspect you're looking for is in this Nean Settlement.
你们在追查的红色嫌犯 就在这个涅安居留地里
How do you know that?
你怎么会知道
You're from Aletheia, right?
你是真理部的人吧
My mission is to search for a special Nean that can transform into red combat mode.
我的任务是搜索 能够转换红色战斗形态的特殊涅安
Are you saying the suspect is a Nean?
那个是涅安吗
Then why don't you use the authority of Aletheia to get into the settlement?
那你用真理部的权限 进入居留地不就得了
This is a classified mission.
这可是机密任务
Therefore, I can't act blatantly.
所以不能明目张胆地行动
And we're all after the same target.
而我们都在追查同一个目标
So…
所以呢…
What's in it for me?
我有什么好处
I'll tell you who the red guy is. What do you think?
那个红色家伙的真实身份…如何
Although I don't like the Aletheia.
虽然我不太喜欢真理部…
Fine, deal.
好 成交
Wait.
请等一下
We can't open the door without permission.
没有许可 我们不能开门
We need to talk to the chief first.
要先跟上头联络…
The opponent is no ordinary person.
对手可不是普通人物
Even the security force could be at risk.
维安部队也有可能会有危险
It's too late if something happens.
要是出了什么事就来不及了
Lurking on the settlement is the suspect in the murder of Roy Junghardt.
潜伏在居留地里的 是罗伊・容格哈特杀害事件的嫌犯
If you refuse to cooperate with Ochrona's investigation and let the suspect escape,
要是你们拒绝配合守护局的调查 让嫌犯趁机逃走
can you take that responsibility?
你们能负起这个责任吗
Open the door.
开门
WELLSTOWN, NEAN SETTLEMENT
(威尔士镇 涅安居留地)
Thank you for your cooperation.
感谢配合
This power is so addictive.
权力 感觉会让人沉迷啊
If we go through here, we'll reach the south part of Wellstown.
只要穿过这里 就能抵达威尔士镇的南端
Although there may be guards,
虽然可能会有人看守
I assume it would be no problem for you with your power.
只要使用露琼小姐的能力 我想应该是没问题的
KEEP OUT
(禁止进入)
Looks like we can't get any closer.
感觉已经无法再靠近了
DUMA 171
(仲马171)
Hey, Aletheia guy.
喂 真理部的
Do you really know who that red guy is?
你真的知道 那个红色家伙的真实身份吗
Where is she?
人呢
Looks like she ran away.
看来被她跑了呢
What do you mean by "my power"?
"只要使用我的能力"是什么意思
Because… Aren't you a special Nean?
因为…你不是特殊涅安吗
You thought I am a human, right?
你不是认为我是人类吗
How did you know I am a Nean?
为何会知道我是涅安
What?
咦
Well…
那个…
I think I heard that from someone at CFN.
好像是听CFN的谁说的吧
You're not a member of CFN.
你不是CFN成员
Why were you there?
为什么会出现在那里
Did Yubal really send you to find me?
犹巴真的有叫你来找我过去吗
Did you already know that Yubal was dead?
你是不是早就知道犹巴已经死了
Did you kill him?
犹巴是你杀的
Although this is just Duma's speculation.
虽然这是仲马的推测就是了
No.
不是的
Are you looking for someone?
在找人吗
I didn't kill him.
我没有杀他
I was just asked to take you to him.
只是有人要我带你去找他…
Who?
谁叫你做的
I was just trying to help.
我只是想帮上忙罢了…
If there's anything I can do,
如果有我能做到的事
I am willing to do it.
我什么都愿意去做…
I don't want to see that man in pain anymore.
我不想再看见那个人痛苦的样子了…
So…
所以
No, we are different.
不对 不一样
I'm not like you guys.
我跟你们才不一样
What?
什么
CODE EVE.
CODE…EVE…
It's all your fault.
都是你的错
I've heard it all. Yubal acted like he's a good guy,
我都听说了 犹巴摆出好人的样子
but secretly killed all the Neans that get in the way.
把所有碍事的涅安全都杀光
And you work for him.
而你就是他的手下
-No, no. -I've also heard
-不…不是的 -我还听说
that your true identity is the Red Devil stained with the blood of your kin.
你的真实身份就是 身体被同胞之血所染红的红色恶魔
Actually, I wanted to fight with Rouge.
其实我是想和露琼战斗的
Desire surges.
欲望高涨
Exactly. Be faithful to your desires,
没错 忠实于欲望
face your desires,
直面欲望
be honest about your desires,
坦诚欲望
and release your desires.
释放欲望
You want to fight, kill,
想要战斗 想要杀人
and destroy,
想要破坏
and couldn't endure anymore.
不能忍耐
But life is so constrained that it can't be as you wish.
但是人生就是如此不自由 不能如人所愿
You're a grown-up and you have to learn to endure.
你都是大人了 要学着忍耐才行
You are right.
你说得没错
So I'll just endure with a substitute for now.
所以我就用代替品忍耐一下吧
Looks like you're a pretty troubled maker.
看来你也是个挺麻烦的人物呢
Rouge.
露琼…
I can't believe you still can resist.
你还能挣扎吗
That's impressive.
真是了不起
You are…
你是…
Dr. Afdal.
阿夫戴尔医生
The agent Yubal mentioned is…
犹巴所说的内应是…
Doctor is not a bad guy.
医生不是坏人
He just got involved.
他只是被卷进来而己
He was asked by Duma to kill Yubal.
他被仲马拜托要杀死犹巴…
He's so worried.
他很苦恼…
I don't want him to do that.
我不想让医生去做那种事…
Doctor.
医生
I did it.
我做到了哦
Then, you are free.
这么一来 医生你就自由了
Please take me with you.
请带我一起走吧
I want to become someone like you.
我也想成为跟医生一样的人
For everyone, I will join you to be free.
为了大家…跟医生一起 我也要获得自由
That's just an illusion.
那只不过是幻觉罢了
What?
咦
I wasn't worried at all.
我并不觉得苦恼
I didn't ask you to help me.
也不需要请求你的帮助
You took it upon yourself to think so and do so.
这是你擅自这么想 擅自做出的事
Doctor.
医生…
What?
咦
I'm not who you think I am.
我并不是你所以为的那种人
Lurking on the settlement, watching the CFN
潜伏在居留地里监视CFN
and saving those Neans
以及拯救那些涅安
are just missions I have to do.
都只不过是完成被交付的任务罢了
Freedom is an illusion.
自由也都是幻觉
There's no such thing as freedom in the outside world.
外头的世界不可能会有什么自由
Humans are definitely not free.
人类也绝对不是自由的
But,
只不过…
those unconscious humans may be more stupid than we are.
那些毫无自觉的人类 或许比我们更加愚蠢也说不定
Afdal.
阿夫戴尔
It's electromagnetic interference.
是电磁干扰
It can't be wrong.
错不了的
It's that guy.
是那个家伙
That red guy is right here.
红色家伙在这里
Rouge.
露琼
Looks like the show has begun.
看来表演开始了
Too bad I can't be there to see it. If it is possible,
可惜我无法现场目睹 有机会的话
let's meet again in the VIP seats.
我们在特等席再见吧
Goodbye.
再见
What's your name again?
啊…你叫什么名字来着
Naomi.
直美
Naomi Orthmann.
直美・奥德曼
Goodbye then.
再见了
Naomi.
直美
You and I are pathetic beings.
我和你都是可悲的存在
This mist is…
这阵雾是…
Yes.
没错
It's the nerve gas generated in my body.
这是由我体内所生成的神经毒气
I don't want this body at all.
我根本就不想拥有这种身体…
I won't be affected by it…
我才不会因为这种东西…
Stop resisting.
别再抵抗了
Both you and I are pathetic beings.
你和我一样 都是可悲的存在
We are not the same.
才不一样
I am not pathetic at all.
我才不可悲…
You want freedom.
你也想得到自由
You, Leon, and I are all the same.
跟里昂还有我是一样的
No.
不对…
There's only one way to get freedom.
要获得自由只有一个办法
Why did you refuse?
为何要拒绝
Get your freedom, Rouge.
获得自由吧 露琼
Verde.
维杜
Right.
没错…
Whether it's me or you,
不论是我…还是你…
if we want to get freedom…
想获得自由的话…